<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Developer's Corner" id="de.ovgu.featureide.core.winvmj.ui.doc.setup">
    <intro>
        <description>
            <b>Developer's Corner</b><br/><br/>
            This section explains how to develop the WinVMJ plugin. Follow these steps and familiarize yourself with the important classes to get started with plugin development.<br/><br/>
            <b>Let's dive into the development process!</b>
        </description>
    </intro>

    <item title="Opening Plugin Projects">
        <description>
            <b>Opening Plugin Projects</b><br/><br/>
            1. Open your <b>Eclipse IDE</b>.<br/>
            2. Select <b>File &gt; Open projects from file system...</b><br/>
            3. Click <b>Directory</b>, and then select where the <b>de.ovgu.featureide.core.winvmj</b>, <b>de.ovgu.featureide.core.winvmj.feature</b>, and <b>de.ovgu.featureide.core.winvmj.updatesite</b> directories of this repository are located.
        </description>
    </item>

    <item title="Important Classes">
        <description>
            <b>Important Classes</b><br/><br/>
            When developing this plugin, you will most likely work with the following classes:<br/><br/>
            - <b>WinVMJCorePlugin</b>: the activator class of this plugin.<br/>
            - <b>WinVMJComposer</b>: the composer class of this plugin.<br/>
            - <b>WinVMJFMComposer</b>: the FM composer class of this plugin. Implemented to disable feature order due to the Delta-Oriented Programming (DOP) approach.<br/>
            - <b>WinVMJProduct</b>: a class that defines a WinVMJ product variation based on config or generated product.<br/>
            - <b>SourceCompiler</b>: utility class used to compile a generated product into runnable JARs.<br/>
            - <b>TemplateRenderer</b>: abstract class that can be extended to generate artifacts with Freemarker Template Engine. All templates should be stored in <b>resources/templates</b>.<br/>
            - <b>InternalResourceManager</b>: utility class used to export assets from <b>resources</b>.
        </description>
    </item>
</cheatsheet>
